Mohammad Durrani

Data Scientist - New York City Data Science Academy

Elmhurst, NY - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Mohammad-Durrani/2d45230b4d1de270

Highly motivated and insightful data scientist with a master's degree in biomedical engineering, and a research background in

biotechnology. Passionate in using pr edictive analytics for business impr ovem ent.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

New York City Data Science Academy - February 2017 to Present

Developed and deployed an interactive shiny application to aid homebuyers and investors in visualizing nationwide real estate

trends. Link to app: https://haseebsaccount.shinyapps.io/MHD_Proj1_Shiny/ | http://blog.nycdatascience.com/student -works/zillow/

- Successfully scraped data from fiverr.com to analyze trends in the global freelancing m arket, as a decision-making tool for individuals and businesses looking to outsource. Link: http://blog.nycdatascience.com/student-works/scraping-fiverr/
- Applied machine learning models to predict price fluctuations in Russian real estate for the Sber bank Russian Housing Market

Kaggle com petition. Link: http://blog.nycdatascience.com/student -works/data-scientists-guide- predicting-housing- prices-russia/

• Delivered an in-depth cluster analysis of Twitter data with a focus on human interactions as a valuable resource for data science

and business gr owth. Link: https://blog.nycdatascience.com/student -works/cluster-analysis-twitter/

Staff Associate

Columbia University Medical Center, Center for Radiological Research - January 2013 to May 2017

- Gener ated r adiation dose-response data to be used in the development of a regr ession model to predict radiation dosage in exposed individuals.
- Collaborated with partnering biotech institutions to develop a diagnostic kit for field testing individual data in the event of a lar ge- scale radiological event.
- Optimized the data flow pipeline with python scripts for high-throughput barcode labeling of sample slides for imaging and analysis
- Presented analysis of experiment data to managem ent at weekly teleconferences, and monthly meetings.

Research Assistant

New York Blood Center - October 2010 to January 2013

- Analyzed data to be used for screening potential antibodies to be used in the development of a malaria vaccine.
- As a side pr oject, studied the efficacy of a potential com pound to be used to inactivat e any par asites present in donor blood before transfusion.
- W orked on a pr oject analyzing the presence of Babesia parasite in human red blood cells.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Biomedical Engineering

NYU Tandon School of Engineering 2010

Bachelor of Science in Biology/Chemistr

Saint John's University 2007

SKILLS

Boosting (Less than 1 year), Clustering (Less than 1 year), Excel (Less than 1 year), Git (Less than 1 year), Hadoop (Less than 1 year)

LINKS

http://blog.nycdatascience.com/author/haseeb_dhotmail

http://github.com/haseebd

http://linkedin.com/in/haseeb-durrani

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

SKILLS

- Python (Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, Principal Component Analysis Version Control (Git, Github) Matplotlib, Scikit-Learn, Statsmodels,
- Clustering (K-means, Hier archical) Natural Language Processing

NLTK, Gensim) • Topic M odeling (Latent Dirichlet

• R (dplyr, tidyr, ggplot2, Plotly, Shiny, • Linear/Logistic Regression

Allocation, Non-negative Matrix

Leaflet, glmnet, randomForest, car et) • Linear/Quadr atic Discriminant Analysis

- MySQL, sqlite3 Factorization)
- Matlab Ridge and Lasso Regularization W eb Scraping (Scrapy, Selenium,
- Jupyter Notebook Random For est/Gradient Boosting BeautifulSoup)
- RStudio Hadoop
- Support Vector Machines
- Excel, W ord, Power point Hive
- Time Series Analysis
- Spark